{
    "id": "277feaf05afb417085f898941e8aafb5",
    "title": "Subordinate Clauses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Here is the money that you lent me.",
            "description": "Here the subordinate clause ‘that you lent me’ modifies the noun money. Hence it is an adjective clause.",
            "answers": [
                "Noun clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Adverb clause"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The person who leaves last should put the lights out.",
            "description": "Here the subordinate clause ‘who leaves last’ modifies the noun person.",
            "answers": [
                "Noun clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Adverb clause"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "This is the house that I told you about.",
            "description": "Here the subordinate clause ‘that I told you about’ modifies the noun house.",
            "answers": [
                "Noun clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Adverb clause"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "People are sleeping out on the streets because there are not enough houses.",
            "description": "Here the subordinate clause ‘because there are no enough houses’ gives the reason for the action mentioned in the main clause. Hence it is an adverb.",
            "answers": [
                "Noun clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Adverb clause"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I knew that I should write to her, but I forgot.",
            "description": "Here the subordinate clause ‘that I should write to her’ is the object of the verb knew. Hence it is a noun clause.",
            "answers": [
                "Noun clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Adverb clause"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Does anyone know where Janet lives?",
            "description": "Here the subordinate clause ‘where Janet lives’ acts as the object of the verb know. Hence it is a noun clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "Noun clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Adverb clause"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "James replied that he was feeling better.",
            "description": "Here the subordinate clause ‘that he was feeling better’ acts as the object of the verb replied. Hence it is a noun clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "Noun clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Adverb clause"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Come in quietly so that she does not hear you.",
            "description": "Here the subordinate clause ‘so that she does not hear you’ gives the purpose of the action mentioned in the main clause. Hence it is a subordinate adverb clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "Noun clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Adverb clause"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I always knew that I could trust you.",
            "description": "Here the subordinate clause ‘that I could trust you’ acts as the object of the verb knew. Hence it is a noun clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "Noun clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Adverb clause"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The scales broke when I was weighing myself this morning.",
            "description": "Here the subordinate clause ‘when I was weighing myself this morning’ gives the time of the action mentioned in the main clause. Hence it is an adverb clause of time.",
            "answers": [
                "Noun clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Adverb clause"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If you are ever in London, come and see me.",
            "description": "This is an adverb clause of condition because it expresses a condition. ",
            "answers": [
                "Noun clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Adverb clause"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The woman who was sitting behind the reception desk gave me a big smile.",
            "description": "Here the subordinate clause ‘who was sitting behind the reception desk’ modifies the noun woman. Hence it is an adjective clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "Noun clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Adverb clause"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}